One, two, three, four.
一、二、三、四
Good morning.
早安
What are you doing?
你在做什么啊？
I came to the office early so I was exercising to prepare for work.
我今天早到了些 要为待会儿的工作做点准备运动
You're always full of energy.
你总是那么充满干劲啊
This is not a gym.
这里不是健身房
My body is out of shape because we haven't had any inspections.
最近没什么稽核工作 我的身体都要生锈了
I have good news, Ms. Hanasaki.
那我有个好消息呢 花琦
Inspection?
是稽核吗？
It's not an inspection, but…
不是稽核
We're going to be helping the Inspection Unit for two days.
而是接下来这两天 我们要去支援检查部
Help the Inspection Unit?
支援检查部？
They are short-handed for credit examinations.
他们需要人手帮忙做信用检查
What is a credit examination?
信用检查是干什么的？
It's to check whether the loans are processed correctly at the branches.
就是确认各分行的融资是否处理正当
Mr. Soma was in the Finance Department so he will be a big help.
相马是前融资课职员 一定帮得上忙
I don't know much about loans.
可是我对融资的事不太了解呢
You'll just be tagging along, like an extra.
所以你这次只是当跟班 也就是多余的
An extra?
多余的？
It's the Fukagawa Branch.
地点是深川分行哦
I'm lucky. It's close to my house.
真幸运 就在我家附近呢
I wouldn't say that you're lucky.
我可不觉得这是幸运
Why?
为什么？
Fukagawa's Branch Manager is in the…
因为深川分行的分行经理…
Shindo faction.
-是真藤派的
Exactly.
就是这样
I feel sick.
心情突然变不好了
That's not all, either.
也不只有这一点
What else is there?
还有什么？
It's Chief Himuro, the leader of the credit examination.
这次信用检查的负责人是冰室主任
Who is he?
冰室主任是谁？
People call him the Branch Crusher.
人们称他为分行破坏狂
Branch Crusher?
分行破坏狂？
If he finds even a single error he will attack you mercilessly,
只要他发现一个小失误 就会豪不留情地展开攻击
damaging your body and soul.
直到对方身心灵受创 体无完肤
That's what I heard.
我是这么听说的
Not a single weed will be able grow on the path that Chief Himuro passes through.
据说冰室主任所经之处 必定寸草不生啊
You two are being overly dramatic.
你们两个也太夸张了吧
I'm sure people are just exaggerating these rumors.
我肯定这些谣言只是越说越离谱而已
You're from Branch Inspection?
你们就是分行稽核班吗？
Yes. I am Soma.
是的 我是相马
-I am Hanasaki-- -Last name only.
-我是花琦… -名字就不用说了
Sorr--
对不…
I'm Himuro, from the Inspection Unit.
我是检查部的冰室
I will head the credit examination.
我将负责领导这次的信用检查
Please follow my instructions. Understand?
请你们服从我的指示 明白了吗？
Yes, sir.
-明白了
-Work hard. -Yes.
-麻烦你了 -是
-I heard that you were a teller.
-听说你以前是出纳员啊？ -是的
What is HR thinking? They don't understand what credit examination does at all.
人事部到底是怎么想的？ 怎么派连信用检查都不懂的人给我？
Why call a former teller?
还是前任出纳员？
She'll only slow us down.
只不过是碍手碍脚罢了
Listen.
听好了
Credit examination is to find and correct unforgivable errors
所谓的信用检查 就是在注重信誉的银行之中
in a bank where trust is a priority.
找出并纠正不可存在的错误
Yes.
是
We have to right the wrongs and protect the justice of the bank.
我们必须矫正错误 维护银行的正义
In other words, it's a job to improve Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
换句话说 这是令东京第一银行变得更好的工作
Yes.
是
I doubt an amateur will be of help,
我不认为你这样的门外汉可以胜任
but I will have to follow HR's decision.
不过 我只能遵照人事部的指示
I want to ask you for one thing.
我只想拜托你一件事
Don't slow us down.
别扯我们后退
Yes, sir.
是
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK FUKAGAWA BRANCH
（东京第一银行深川分行）
Hanasaki. Let me repeat this just in case.
花琦 我再叮嘱你一次
Don't ever say anything unnecessary to Chief Himuro.
在冰室主任面前 不准说任何多余的话
Yes.
是
What's with that face?
你这是什么表情？
I'm not quite sure if I can do that.
我不太能保证
Come on.
我求求你了
Bear with it for just two days.
只要忍耐两天而己
Let's go.
走吧
Thank you for your time.
这次麻烦你们了
I am Branch Manager Tayama.
我是分行经理田山
I'm Kitamura of the Finance Department.
我是融资课课长北村 请多指教
This is the list of companies that are subject to inspection.
这是这次要检查的公司清单
Please bring the credit files.
请将信用资料档案交给我们
Yes, sir.
好的
If we find any loans in question,
如果我们发现任何融资项目有问题
we will conduct strict training on it during a review meeting at 4 p.m.
就会在下午4点的检讨会上 进行严格指导
Yes, sir.
知道了
-One more thing. -Yes?
-还有一件事 -是
I am a little hot.
这里有点热呢
Can you change the AC setting?
能不能调一下空调？
I will check it right away.
我马上去看
Anything else?
还有其他的吗？
Nothing in particular.
没别的事了
Yes, sir.
是
Just as I heard, Mr. Himuro seems to be a very difficult person.
正如传闻一样 这个冰室主任真是不好应付呢
Yes. We have to be prepared.
是啊 还是先做好准备吧
Yes.
好
-Ms. Hanasaki. -Yes.
-花琦小姐 -是
Go help the Finance Department.
你去支援融资课
Yes.
是
Collect files, make copies, make tea,
搬运资料 复印 泡茶之类的杂事
and do all miscellaneous tasks.
都由你来做
Yes.
是
That's all you can do anyway.
反正你也只能做这些了
Smile.
微笑
I won't get beaten down!
我不会认输的
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
Tomeoka Logistics.
富冈物流
Okuzawa Corporation.
奥泽股份有限公司
Sugikawa Construction.
杉川建材
Narikura Construction…
成仓建设
-Excuse me. -Oogoshi Estate.
-打扰了 -大越房产
Mr. Kitamura. I came to help.
北村课长 我是来帮忙的
You are…
你是…
I am Hanasaki.
我是分行稽核班的花琦
I'm here to help out today.
今天是来支援的
Hanasaki?
花琦？
-Etou? -Hi. Long time no see. How are you?
-江藤？ -好久不见 你很有精神嘛
Do you know each other?
你们认识吗？
Yes, we were colleagues.
是 我们是同期的
I see.
原来如此
You work at headquarters? You're climbing up the ladder.
你在本部工作啊？ 看来你是如鱼得水呢
Not at all. I'm only being used for miscellaneous tasks.
才不是呢 我也是被叫来打杂的
How about you, Etou?
你呢 江藤？
Since when are you in Finance?
你什么时候开始在融资课的？
Since two years ago. My wish finally came true.
两年前吧 我总算达成愿望了
I see. You are working hard.
这样啊 你很拼命呢
You too.
你也是啊
There are so many documents.
资料还真多啊
There are more. They will check about 100 companies a day.
不只这些呢 他们一天要检查一百多家公司
That many?
那么多？
Excuse me.
打扰了
Check thoroughly and look for
一定要仔细检查
anything that is questionable or unclear.
找出可疑或不明确的地方
Yes, sir.
是
The companies in question will be brought up at the review meeting,
有问题的公司会在检讨会被提出来
and I will investigate it.
之后我会好好追问
I understand.
我明白了
Keep in mind that this is a task to improve the bank.
记住 这是能让银行变得更好的工作
Yes, sir.
好的
Listen.
听好了
Don't cut corners.
不准马马虎虎
Yes, sir.
-是
-Foul play with credit examination? -Yes.
-透过信用检查进行不正当行为？ -是的
We received an anonymous tip.
我们收到一则匿名告发
It says that Mr. Himuro threatens Branch Managers and Chiefs of Finance
指控冰室主任会在每次信用检查时
whenever he goes in for inspection.
威胁分行经理和融资课课长
By threatening, you mean…
是怎样的威胁呢？
He finds faults with the branches and blackmails them to extort money.
他会找出分行的错误作为把柄 敲诈他们的钱
Extortion…
敲诈？
We found out that although Mr. Himuro is notorious for his severe inspections,
我们发现冰室主任 以严格执行信用检查为名
his evaluation has been varied the last two to three years.
但他过去两、三年的评价时有差异
The results of the credit examination influences personnel evaluations.
而他的人事考核 是受到信用检查的结果所影响
So it might be possible.
所以这件事也是有可能的
So you'd like us to investigate this a little further?
所以 你们想要我们再进一步调查吗？
It's like an undercover investigation.
对 这次就像卧底调查一样
I understand.
我明白了
Please make sure Mr. Himuro doesn't find out.
确保别让冰室主任起疑心
Then it's better not to tell Hanasaki.
这样的话 最好别让花琦知道吧？
I agree. She's too transparent.
我同意 她行事太明显了
Yes.
是啊
Mr. Soma. What's wrong?
相马 怎么了吗？
Nothing.
没什么
-Ms. Hanasaki. -Yes.
-花琦小姐 -是
-Make ten copies. -Yes, sir.
-这个拿去复印十份 -好的
And get coffee for everyone.
还有 给大家泡个咖啡
Yes, sir.
好的
-Ms. Hanasaki. -Yes?
-花琦小姐 -是
-No sugar for me. -Yes.
-我的不要加糖
Congratulations on the merger and acquisition in New York.
关于完成纽约企业并购一事 真是恭喜你了
I just happened to be lucky this time. It's no big deal.
我这次只是运气好罢了 没什么大不了的
That was not just luck.
这可不是运气呢
Everyone says the next President will be you, Mr. Doujima.
大家都说下一任行长肯定是你呢 堂岛专务
That's just because I became the Senior Executive Director.
那是看我刚当上常务执行董事 说的客气话吧
No. I'm sure Executive Director Shindo is feeling impatient.
不 我想真藤常务一定也很着急
Hello, Executive Director Shindo.
你好 真藤常务
How are you, Senior Executive Director Doujima?
辛苦你了 堂岛专务
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR'S ROOM
（常务执行董事办公室）
Those are just rumors people are saying to please them.
那些传言只是阿谀奉承的话罢了
-Mr. Kodama. -Yes.
-儿玉 -是
One small scratch can become lethal.
一个小小的漏洞也可能会致命
-We must be even more cautious. -Yes.
-我们一定要更加谨慎才行 -是
You never know what will happen until we see the results.
结果出来之前 我们都不知道会发生什么事
That goes for both them and us.
我们双方都不知道
You're right.
你说得对
Hello, Branch Manager Tayama?
喂 是田山经理吗？
It's been a while, Mr. Kodama.
好久不见 儿玉次长
I believe the Fukagawa Branch is now under credit examination.
深川分行现在正接受信用检查吧？
Yes.
是的
The review meeting will start soon.
检讨会马上要开始了
Let me ask, just in case.
只是以防万一 我想请问
You don't have any problems with the loans, do you?
融资方面没出什么问题吧？
Of course not.
当然没有
I heard that Chief Himuro of the Inspection Unit is very tough.
我听说检查部的冰室主任很难搞呢
Please be careful.
请务必小心
Yes.
是
Even a small scratch by his subordinates
我们这些手下 如果犯下一个小小的漏洞
can affect the next presidential race for Executive Director Shindo.
就可能会影响到 真藤常务争夺下一任行长的事
Please bear that in mind.
请务必铭记于心
I understand.
我明白了
Please be careful.
那就拜托你了
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK FUKAGAWA BRANCH
（东京第一银行深川分行）
CREDIT EXAMINATION REVIEW MEETING DAY ONE
（信用检查检讨会第一天）
What is going on here?
这是怎么回事？
26 out of 94 companies
我们今天检查的94家公司之中
we've examined today are reported to have some issues.
居然有26间有问题
That's almost a third!
那几乎是三成呢
The Fukagawa Branch is slacking off.
看来深川分行的管理相当松懈啊
I am sorry.
非常抱歉
The Finance Department is the backbone of the branch.
融资课可说是分行的中枢
Look how bad it is.
这到底成何体统？
This reveals the level of this branch.
真是反映出了这间分行的水准呢
We have to review many companies.
我们需要检讨很多家公司
First company is Fukagawa Print.
首先是深川印刷
-Who is in charge? -I am.
-负责人是谁？ -是我
The Section Chief?
课长你亲自负责吗？
Yes. Their performance was down so I took that on myself.
是的 他们的业绩不是很好 所以由我负责
What kind of company is this?
这是什么样的公司？
It's a mid-sized printing company and--
这是一家中型印刷公司…
Do you think that I can't read the credit files?
你以为我看不懂信用资料档案吗？
No…
不是的
I am asking you for information that is not written here.
我想知道的是这上面没有写的资讯
I'm sorry.
很抱歉
Their performance is down the last six months.
他们近半年的业绩都不是很理想
It might go bankrupt anytime.
随时可能会破产
But they received funding of 30 million yen last month
却在上个月收到三千万的资金
and used it to pay their customers.
用作支付客户的费用
How did they get it?
他们是怎么得到资金的？
Is it from other banks?
是从其他银行贷款的吗？
I don't know exactly.
这个我不是很清楚
What?
什么？
They seem to have borrowed it from somewhere.
好像是从某处借来的
"Seem" to? What is that?
“好像”？那是什么意思？
You are in charge of Fukagawa Print.
你是深川印刷的负责人吧？
Yes.
是的
How come you don't know the source of the 30 million yen?
那你怎么会不清楚 那三千万是怎么来的？
I am sorry.
真的很抱歉
How are you the Section Chief of Finance?
你到底是怎么当上融资课课长的啊？
Isn't he being too mean?
这样说有点太过分了吧？
Hey! No talking.
那边的 不准聊天
I'm sorry.
对不起
The level of this branch is really low.
这间分行的水准还真低呢
I don't think you're training them well, Branch Manager Tayama.
我觉得你没把他们训练好啊 田山经理
I'm sorry.
真的十分抱歉
Next!
下一个
Checking the main figures, is not enough for cases like these.
像这样的案子 只是看表面的数据是没什么用的
I'm sorry.
对不起
Thoroughly check all the additional statements.
必须仔细查看所有附带的详细内容
To whom and how much are they selling? Who are they paying?
他们的客户是谁？ 售价多少？又支付给谁？
Important information is hidden there.
重要的资讯往往隐藏其中
Yes.
是的
How long have you been working in Finance?
你在融资课做多久了？
Two years.
两年
That's why.
怪不得
You're a rookie, so you're spoiled.
还是个菜鸟 所以被惯坏了呢
I'm not…
才不是…
If you can't discern these things at a glance,
如果不能一眼就察觉这些东西
you're not suited for Finance.
那你也不适合融资课吧？
In fact, you're disqualified as a banker.
不对 是没资格当银行职员
-I'm sorry. -Next!
-很抱歉 -下一个
Who is in charge of Machiyama?
町山建设公司的负责人是谁？
I am.
是我
They've been in the red for three consecutive terms.
他们已经连续三期财务赤字
But got an additional 20 million yen in June.
却在6月获得两千万日元的追加贷款
Why is that?
这是怎么回事？
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行深川分行）
The loans at this branch are of the lowest level.
这家分行的融资课是水准最低的
This is the bottom of Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
简直是东京第一银行最差劲的分行
That's caused by your low sense of awareness as bankers.
原因在于 你们身为银行职员的意识感太弱了
With all due… Ouch!
请恕我… 好痛
What is it?
干嘛？
No…
没…
Nothing.
没事
That's all for today.
今天就到此为止
Branch Manager Tayama, I'm warning you.
田山经理 我先提醒你
At this rate,
看今天的状况
I may have to question your qualifications as a Branch Manager.
说不定明天我就要质疑你 有没有资格当这个分行经理了
What is wrong with that damn chief!
那个混蛋主任到底算什么东西啊？
Hanasaki, you are too loud and you have a bad mouth.
花琦 你太大声了 而且没句好话
He is right. There are other customers.
是有 还有其他顾客呢
-Here you go. -Sorry.
-来 -对不起
Hey.
真是的
But he just wanted to pick on them.
但那家伙只是在挑人家毛病啊
He kept on endlessly nitpicking tiny errors.
一直在鸡蛋里挑那些看不见的骨头
There's someone like that?
有这样的人啊？
Yes. He's so arrogant and condescending just because no one can talk back to him.
是啊 因为没人反驳他 就摆出一副傲慢自大的样子
-He's abusing his power and position? -Yes.
-这是仗势欺人吧？ -对啊
He releases his stress like that?
是想要借此释放压力吗？
Exactly.
完全没错
He said they were at the "bottom" and "disqualified as a banker."
他说什么 “差劲”、“没资格当银行职员”…
-Who does he think he is? -Be quiet.
-他以为他是谁啊？ -安静点啦
Etou?
江藤
Hanasaki.
花琦
Steamed pike conger. This is on us.
这是蒸笼海鳗 我请客
Are you sure?
这样好吗？
Yes. It's a welcome dish.
是的 欢迎你们光临
Thank you.
-谢谢
I didn't know that this was your dad's restaurant, Hanasaki.
真没想到这是你爸的店呢 花琦
But the name of the restaurant is Hanasaki.
可是店名就是花琦啊
I didn't put two and two together.
我没联想到嘛
-We've been wanting to come here. -Yes.
-我们一直想来这家店呢 -是啊
We heard that this place is good.
我们听说这里的食物很好吃
Hanasaki's father's dishes are really tasty.
花琦她爸爸做的菜真的很好吃
Thank you very much.
真是谢谢你们啊
Branch Manager Tayama came here before too.
田山经理也来过这里哦
Really?
真的吗？
Please come again. Since we are neighbors.
你们分行就在附近 今后请多多关照
We will.
我们会常来光顾的
Wow. This steamed pike conger is the best.
天啊 这道蒸笼海鳗也太厉害了吧
I'm so glad.
我好开心啊
By the way, Mr. Etou. Are you married?
对了 江藤先生 你结婚了吗？
-Dad. -No.
-爸 -还没呢
Oh, really?
真的吗？
-Please introduce him to someone. -Sure.
-请帮他介绍个好对象吧 -没问题
He is the same age.
不只是同期 而且还是同龄
A little young, but looks healthy. He is nice and his workplace is close by.
虽然有点年轻 但看起来很健康 品性良好 而且工作单位就在附近
Dad, we can hear everything.
爸 你的心声我们都听得见啦
Mai, your dream of becoming a banker's wife is just within reach.
小舞 你要成为 银行职员妻子的梦想快要实现了
I've never dreamed of such a thing.
我没有那种梦想啦
This is not funny anymore.
而且这样很没意思耶
Yes, it is.
-不会啊 多有意思啊
Mr. Soma.
相马
-Same here. -Nice.
-我们心意相通呢 -就是说啊
BRANCH MANAGER'S OFFICE
（分行经理办公室）
Yes.
请进
Mr. Himuro.
冰室主任
Is there anything wrong?
有什么事情吗？
I wanted to talk to you.
我有些话想对你说
Yes.
好的
Tomorrow is daunting.
明天也很可怕啊
I know.
就是说啊
He just loves making sarcastic remarks.
他就喜欢冷言冷语 小题大做
I get so mad when I think about Chief Himuro.
我一想到那个冰室主任就火大
-What? -Hanasaki.
-什么？ -花琦
Let me remind you that we are in the Inspection Unit right now.
我提醒你一下 我们现在是检查部这边的人哦
Sorry.
抱歉
But it angers me to see him using his power and position
但是 一想到他仗着自己的地位和权力
against people in the branch just to release his stress.
把分行的员工当成宣泄压力的对象 我就超级火大
Well, I was thinking the same thing too.
我也是这么想
I don't mind.
我还好
Since I am not as good as my other colleagues in the Finance Department.
毕竟 我确实 没像融资课的其他同事那么优秀
But he was so harsh on you, Mr. Kitamura.
不过 他对北村课长你真是太苛刻了
It can't be helped.
也没办法啊
Don't say that.
怎么能那样呢？
He shouldn't have attacked you about Fukagawa Print.
他不应该用深川印刷的事情 对你人身攻击啊
-Etou! -It was the Branch Manager--
-江藤 -明明是分行经理他…
Etou!
江藤
Fukagawa Print is the company that received the 30 million yen fund
深川印刷是那家不知从哪里
from an unknown source?
凑到三千万资金的公司吧？
Yes. Mysterious 30 million yen.
对 谜一般的三千万
Is there anything else?
那家公司怎么了吗？
Well, nothing.
那个啊 没什么
Don't say unnecessary things.
别说多余的话
-I'm sorry. -Mr. Kitamura.
-对不起 -北村课长
We won't tell Mr. Himuro.
我们不会跟冰室主任说的
We came to help the Inspection Unit this time,
我们这次虽然是为了支援检查部而来
but Branch Inspection supports everyone in the branch.
可是分行稽核班的宗旨 是帮助分行的所有职员啊
Fukagawa Print is run by a friend of the Branch Manager.
深川印刷是田山经理的朋友经营的
Everyone in our branch knows it.
分行的人都知道这件事
No one mentions it, and it's like an unspoken rule.
但没人会提起 就像默认事实一样
Since they're a customer of the branch office,
由于他们算是田山经理的客户
I can't investigate too far.
我也不能深入调查
I didn't know what to answer when I was asked those questions today.
所以今天被问到那些问题的时候 我也不知道要怎么回答
I see.
原来如此
That's wrong of the Branch Manager.
那就是田山经理不对了
Mr. Himuro was attacking Mr. Kitamura badly,
刚才冰室主任那样攻击北村课长
but he didn't say anything.
他却坐在那边一语不发
-You are right. -It's okay.
-就是啊 -算了 没关系啦
I wonder how things will go tomorrow.
不知道明天怎么办呢
Yes.
是啊
There is a company I want to know more about.
其实 有一家公司让我很在意
Which company is it?
哪家公司？
Natsume Mokuzai.
夏目木材
There seems to be an interesting connection with Fukagawa Print,
这家公司 好像跟我们今天检讨过的深川印刷
which we discussed earlier.
有某种关联呢
NATSUME MOKUZAI
（夏目木材公司）
-Um… -Branch Manager Tayama.
-这个… -田山经理
It seems like you are doing something that you should
看来 你做了一些身为一名银行职员
not be doing as a banker.
绝对不能做的事呢
I haven't mentioned this to anyone yet.
我还没跟任何人提起过这件事
But everyone will find out at the meeting tomorrow.
不过 我应该会在明天的检讨会上 让大家知道吧
Can you please refrain from doing that?
这件事…能请你高抬贵手吗？
No. I am in the Inspection Unit,
不行呢 我可是检查部主任
so I can't overlook foul play.
怎么可以助长歪风呢？
Mr. Himuro. Please.
求求你 冰室主任
Doing that would be a huge risk for me.
做那样的事可是要冒着很大风险的
Then what should I do?
那我该怎么办？
Let me see.
让我想想啊
One Section Chief of the Finance Department…
某间分行的融资课长
paid me this much.
给了我这么多
Okay. I promise to pay you that amount tomorrow morning.
我明白了 我明早会交到你手上的
I will rethink it if you say so.
既然你都这么说了 我就再考虑考虑
Please.
拜托你了
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK FUKAGAWA BRANCH
（东京第一银行深川分行）
Good morning.
-早安
NATSUME MOKUZAI
（夏目木材公司）
Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦小姐
Return this to the Finance Department.
-是 -把这个还给融资课
Yes, sir.
好的
But Natsume Mokuzai is on the review list for today.
但是夏目木材 是今天需要检讨的公司之一呢
It's okay.
没关系
It didn't have any problems.
这家公司没什么问题
Is that so?
是这样吗？
Hurry up and go.
快点去吧
Yes, sir.
是
Make sure to check thoroughly and scrutinize every detail.
记得要仔细查看 不要漏掉任何一个细节
Yes.
-是
Oh, it hurts. What is this? It hurts.
好痛 怎么回事？好痛啊
What is it?
怎么了？
Sorry, but my stomach hurts.
不好意思 我肚子有点痛
I might have had too much for breakfast.
可能是早餐吃太多了吧？
I have to go to the bathroom.
我去一下厕所
I have a stomachache.
好痛啊…
What's that?
真是的
My stomach hurts.
我肚子好痛啊
-Hanasaki! -Mr. Soma.
-花琦 -相马
-Let me see that file. -Here.
-让我看看那个文件 -给你
-What's the matter? -Well…
-怎么了吗？ -这个嘛…
I wanted to know why Mr. Himuro excluded this company from the list.
我想知道为什么冰室主任 把这家公司排除在外
Isn't it because it has no problems?
不是说了没问题吗？
No… This company has something.
不对 这家公司有跷蹊
What?
什么？
-Natsume Mokuzai? -Yes.
-夏目木材？ -是的
-Who is in charge? -Me.
-负责人是谁呢？ -是我
How's the business?
他们的业绩怎么样？
Not bad. They are not in the red, nor do they get behind in repayments.
还不错 没有赤字 也没有拖欠还款的情况
Natsume Mokuzai is an old company.
夏目木材是老字号了吧？
-Do you know them? -Yes. It's near my house.
-你听说过吗？ -嗯 就在我家附近
The President comes to my restaurant.
他家社长偶尔也会光顾我们的店
I see.
原来如此
They received an urgent loan addition last month.
他们在上个月 收到了一笔紧急追加贷款 对吧？
Yes. Honestly, I didn't think it would be approved,
是的 我还以为不会通过呢
but the Manager approved it on the same day.
结果田山经理当天就批准了
Same day?
当天？
-May I use the computer? -Please.
-我能借用一下电脑吗？ -可以
NATSUME MOKUZAI INC.
（夏目木材公司）
On July 10th, they withdrew the entire amount they received from the loan.
他们在7月10日获得融资当天 就将全额提出来了
How did they spend that 30 million yen?
他们到底把那三千万 花在什么地方啊？
Weren't you talking about a 30-million-yen fund yesterday?
昨天你不是也提过 什么三千万资金吗？
The mysterious 30 million yen of Fukagawa Print.
深川印刷的谜之三千万
-Yes. -That was also on July 10th.
-就是这个 -那个好像也是发生在7月10日
Fukagawa Print borrowed 30 million yen
深川印刷不知从哪里
from an unknown source,
借来了三千万
and Natsume Mokuzai spent 30 million yen on an unknown source.
而夏目木材又不知为了什么 取出了三千万
Is it just a coincidence that both happened on the same day?
这两件事还发生在同一天 真的只是偶然吗？
Sublease…
是转借
The loan of 30 million yen to Natsume Mokuzai
夏目木材融资的三千万
might have been subleased to Fukagawa Print.
应该是被转借给了深川印刷
What's their connection?
这两家公司有什么关联吗？
I don't think there is any.
应该没什么关联吧？
Right.
是啊
Maybe the Branch Manager is in between them.
会不会是田山经理从中牵线的呢？
Fukagawa Print is run by a friend of the Branch Manager.
深川印刷是田山经理的朋友经营的
What if he asked Natsume Mokuzai to sublease to Fukagawa Print because
会不会是因为银行不能融资给他们 田山经理就拜托夏目木材转借贷款？
the bank can't finance them.
这完全合理呢
Wait a minute. That's a bypass loan.
等等 那不就是逆回融资吗？
I can't believe the Branch Manager would do that.
田山经理居然会做这种事
That's not allowed.
真是不可原谅
It's against the Investment Act.
这可是违反投资法的
But we can't determine that yet.
不过 我们还不能断定
I will go to Natsume Mokuzai.
我去一趟夏目木材吧
I have to investigate the truth.
我想要调查事情的真相
I don't think they will tell you the truth that easily.
但是…他们不会轻易告诉你的
The Branch Manager might be in this with Natsume Mokuzai.
田山经理很有可能和夏目木材是同谋
That President is not that kind of a man.
不 那位社长不是这样的人
I think so too. I'll ask him anyway.
我也是这么认为 让我当面问问他
-I'm coming. -Etou.
-我也一起去 -江藤
I am in charge of Natsume Mokuzai.
毕竟夏目木材的负责人是我啊
-See you later. -See you.
-那我们走了 -待会儿见
I'm ashamed that I didn't notice this even though I was in charge.
身为负责人的我竟然没察觉到 真丢脸啊
I'm disqualified to be in Finance.
我果然不是合格的融资课职员
Why are you being so blue. Cheer up.
别那么失落啊 振作一点
Hey, Mai.
啊 小舞
Dad.
爸
Hello.
你好
Hello, Mr. Etou.
你好 江藤先生
Did you change your business partner from Mr. Soma?
小舞 你的工作搭档 从相马换成江藤先生了吗？
No. It's just today.
不是啦 今天而已
I see. But you look good together.
这样啊 但是你们很相配啊
Did the President of Natsume Mokuzai come to our restaurant recently?
爸 夏目木材的社长 最近有来店里吗？
Mr. Natsume?
夏目社长？
He came last month with the Branch Manager of this bank.
他上个月跟这家分行的经理一起来过
-What? -What? With our Branch Manager?
-什么？ -什么？跟田山经理吗？
Yes.
是啊
I'm sure there is something.
绝对有古怪
-Something? -Thanks, Dad.
-什么古怪？ -谢谢 爸
-Excuse me. -Be careful.
-我先走了 -路上小心
She'll have him under her thumb if they get married.
如果结婚的话 他肯定是个老婆奴啊
NATSUME MOKUZAI
（夏目木材公司）
Hi, Mr. Etou. What's the matter?
江藤先 你怎么来了？
Long time no see.
好久不见
Are you Mai? Mr. Hanasaki's daughter?
咦？你是花琦先生的女儿小舞吧？
Today, I come as an employee of Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
我今天是以东京第一银行的职员身分 前来拜访的
I see.
原来如此
What is it?
有什么事吗？
It is about the loan of 30 million yen we offered last month.
是关于上个月 拨给你们的三千万紧急融资
Ms. Hanasaki. Please copy this file.
花琦小姐 复印一下…
I'm sorry.
不好意思
Hanasaki has a stomachache so she's in the bathroom.
花琦她肚子痛 在上厕所
-She is no help at all. -I'll do it.
-她真是一点忙都帮不上啊 -我来吧
You immediately withdrew 30 million yen.
你好像当天就领出了那三千万
How did you spend that cash?
请问是用来做什么了呢？
I used it as an operating fund.
我用作运转资金了啊
Are you close to Branch Manager Tayama?
请问你和田山经理很熟吗？
My father said you came to his restaurant with him.
我爸说你们上个月 一起来过我们店里呢
That was a coincidence.
那只是巧合啦
Did he ask you to
会不会是他拜托你
sublease 30 million yen to Fukagawa Print?
把那三千万转借给深川印刷呢？
That's nonsense.
没这回事啦
What Branch Manager Tayama did is prohibited as a banker.
田山经理所做的事 是身为银行职员不该做的
If this is left alone, you will also be charged for lending a hand.
这样下去的话 你就会变成包庇他的同谋
What? Is that so?
什么？是这样吗？
Did you sublease 30 million yen to Fukagawa Print?
你是不是把那三千万 转借给了深川印刷？
If he asked you to do such a thing,
如果他真的让你做了这种事
I have the responsibility for not realizing what was happening.
而我身为负责人 却没有察觉到 我也有责任
I am very sorry.
真的十分抱歉
President Natsume. Would you please tell us the truth?
夏目社长 请你把真相告诉我们吧
I promise that we will not cause you trouble.
我保证我们绝不会给你添麻烦
Please.
拜托了
I have a stomachache again.
我肚子又痛了
Excuse me for a moment.
我去一下厕所 不好意思
Branch Inspection is so useless.
分行稽核班真是没用啊
-You scared me. -Please come with me.
-吓死我了 -你过来一下
Did you find out anything?
有什么发现吗？
PROMISSORY NOTE 30 MILLION YEN
（本票 三千万日元）
This is…
这个是…
This is an IOU from Natsume Mokuzai when they
是夏目木材转借三千万
lent 30 million yen to Fukagawa Print.
给深川印刷的本票
Can we use this as evidence of a bypass loan?
这就是逆回融资的证据了吧？
Yes.
是的
It's hard to believe that the Branch Manager did a bypass loan.
真不敢相信 田山经理居然做出逆回融资这种事
President Natsume told me…
夏目社长说…
A small company like us will go down
像我们这种小公司
if the bank turns us down.
如果没有银行支持 很快就经营不下去了
I can't turn down an offer from
所以当田山经理拜托我的时候
a Branch Manager.
我根本就不能拒绝
I can't forgive the Branch Manager.
我无法原谅田山经理
Please investigate this thoroughly.
请你们彻查此事
Mr. Soma.
相马先生
Please bring it up at the review meeting today.
请在检讨会上提出这件事吧
But that means
但那样的话
this branch will have to take responsibility.
你们整间分行都要负责
Yes.
我知道
I don't want to bring shame on the branch,
我也不想让分行丢脸
but involving our customers in something like this
但是 要求我们的客户做出这种事
is unacceptable.
是无法原谅的
I understand.
我知道了
Thank you very much.
-拜托你了
The Branch Manager is horrible.
田山经理也太过分了
I feel bad for the employees.
真是为分行的职员感到难过
What's wrong? You seem unsatisfied.
怎么了？你好像闷闷不乐的
Listen, Hanasaki.
花琦 其实…
Come here.
过来这边
There is one more person who's doing something unacceptable as a banker.
还有一个人 做了身为银行职员不该做的事
Who is it?
谁啊？
Chief Himuro.
冰室主任
There was a report about Chief Himuro's foul play.
有人告发冰室主任的不正当行为
We were sent to help the Inspection Unit
我们这次被派来支援检查部
in order to investigate.
其实是为了调查那件事
Foul play? What do you mean?
不正当行为指的是什么？
He's blackmailing people using errors found in the branch to extort money.
他找出分行的把柄 再用来敲诈相关人员的钱
Mr. Himuro excluded Natsume Mokuzai from the list because of that?
难道冰室主任把夏目木材排除在外 就是因为这个？
He's returning the favor.
他只是在还人情
Since he received money from the Branch Manager
他发现了田山经理的把柄 就用来威胁他
after threatening him.
收取封口费
This is Branch Manager Tayama's account statement.
这是田山经理的账户记录
He withdrew 500,000 yen from this branch's ATM
他于今早8点2分从这里的提款机
at 8:02 a.m. today.
领出了五十万日元
That means this 500,000 yen was hush money?
所以这五十万就是封口费吗？
Probably.
很有可能
Mr. Soma. Let's investigate Chief Himuro.
相马 我们去追问冰室主任吧
No, we can't.
不行
This is Chief Himuro's bank statement.
这是冰室主任的账户记录
There is no money received.
根本没有钱入账
He received money by cash to leave no trace.
他收取的是现金 确保不留痕迹
Then we have no evidence.
这样一来 我们就没证据了
We can prove the bypass loan by Branch Manager Tayama.
我们能够指证 田山经理策划的逆回融资
But it may be difficult to investigate Chief Himuro's foul play.
但要证明冰室主任的不正当行为 就很难了
Then do we have to overlook Chief Himuro?
难道我们只能放任他这么做吗？
It's frustrating, but we have to give up for today.
是很不甘心 但今天也只能放弃了
No way.
怎么可以这样？
He arrogantly told us to correct the wrongdoings,
他那么傲慢地说要纠正不正当行为
while he's doing the opposite.
自己却说一套做一套
This is so wrong!
这样是大错特错啊！
You are too loud!
你太大声了啦
I'm sorry.
抱歉
This is so frustrating.
我太不甘心了
But why didn't you tell me such an important thing?
那么重要的事 你之前怎么没跟我说？
I kept it secret because you can't hide your feelings.
你这个什么心思都藏不住的人 我能告诉你吗？
That's not true.
才不是这样呢
Look! It's clear on your face.
你看 都写在你脸上了
We can nail Chief Himuro and his foul play
如果我们能证明 田山经理今早取出的五十万
if we can prove that he received the 500,000 yen
是交给了冰室主任
that Branch Manager Tayama withdrew this morning, right?
是不是就能揭穿他了？
Yes, but how?
是啊 但是要怎么确认？
Look.
就是那个
Camera?
监控？
I will trace the 500,000 yen.
我要去追查那五十万的下落
Hey, wait!
喂 等等
Oh, my God.
真是的
CREDIT EXAMINATION REVIEW MEETING DAY TWO
（信用检查检讨会第二天）
Let's start the second review meeting.
现在开始第二天的检讨会
First from Hirakawa Chemical.
首先是平川化学股份有限公司
-Who is in charge? -I am.
-负责人是谁？ -是我
I see an equipment fund estimation, but where's
这上面只有设备资金的估价
the transfer details and receipt?
转账资料和发票呢？
That's not ready yet…
那些还没准备好
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Do you think it is over once you offer a loan?
你以为把融资拨出去就完事了吗？
It's important to manage it once the loan is approved.
融资批准之后的管理是很重要的
Here he comes.
来了
What's next?
过来这里了
First, he went to the hallway.
首先过了走廊
Where did he go?
去哪里了？
Let's check.
让我看看
He went this way.
他走过这里
And he opened this door.
然后开了这扇门
NO PARKING
（禁止停车）
The parking lot.
是停车场啊
A 40-million-yen loan is a little excessive for this company, no?
给这家公司四千万的融资额 是不是太高了？
Their performance is expected to improve.
我们预计他们的业绩会增长
How do you know?
根据什么呢？
According to the business plan and the--
根据他们的商业计划…
I am asking if it's absolutely possible.
我是问你怎么肯定业绩会增长？
Don't you have any proof?
你连依据都没有吗？
Here he is.
来了
It's strange that the estimated amount and the amount spent doesn't match.
他们的报价和实际花费的金额有差距 这是很可疑的
I am sorry.
真的很抱歉
Don't you have a sense of responsibility?
你这个人有没有一点责任感啊？
How are you still in the Finance Department?
你怎么还能在融资课干下去啊？
Next!
下一个
I wish I could tell if this is cash.
要是能证明这里面是现金就好了
Bingo!
太好了
I'm sorry.
真的十分抱歉
Next!
下一个
That's all. I will send a list of needed improvements later on.
到此结束 我之后会将需要改善的地方列成清单
Thank you very much.
辛苦了
Excuse me.
不好意思
I would like to review one more company.
我还有一家公司想要检讨一下
-Which company? -Yes.
-哪一家公司？ -是
It's Natsume Mokuzai.
是夏目木材
NATSUME MOKUZAI
（夏目木材公司）
I told you that it had no problems.
我说了 这家没有问题
Actually, it did.
实际上是有的
A 30-million-yen loan was approved
田山经理在7月10日
by the Branch Manager on July 10th.
批准了一笔三千万的融资
Then they withdrew
而他们在同一天
all the cash within the same day.
以现金形式领出了全额
What's wrong with that?
那又怎么样？
Natsume Mokuzai subleased that entire amount to Fukagawa Print, as instructed
然后 夏目木材把那笔钱 原封不动地转借给了深川印刷
by Manager Tayama.
而这是田山经理的指示
Branch Manager Tayama.
田山经理
You were asked for a loan
你受朋友委托
from your friend who runs Fukagawa Print.
帮他经营的深川印刷融资
But Fukagawa Print is in danger of bankruptcy,
但深川印刷已是面临破产的企业
so our bank cannot finance them.
很难得到我们银行的融资
So you planned and executed the bypass loan
于是 你就策划通过夏目木材
by involving Natsume Mokuzai.
实行这次的逆回融资
Am I right?
我说得没错吧？
Why do you have that IOU?
你怎么会有这张票？
I borrowed this from Natsume Mokuzai.
这是我从夏目木材借来的
You forced our customer into committing wrongdoing.
你强迫我们的客户参与不正当行为
This is absolutely prohibited as a banker.
这是银行职员绝不允许做的事
Branch Manager Tayama.
田山经理
I will report this.
这件事我们会向上级报告
This is not what we agreed on, Mr. Himuro.
这跟之前说好的不一样啊 冰室主任
What are you talking about?
你在说什么呢？
Thanks to you, we were able to reveal the wrongdoing.
多亏你揭发这个不正当行为
Great job.
辛苦你了
Wait a moment.
等等
What are you doing here now?
你想干嘛呢？
It is not over yet.
这件事还没有结束
Chief Himuro. You knew about the bypass loan, didn't you?
冰室主任 你其实知道这个逆回融资吧？
What?
什么？
You knew but tried to overlook it.
你发现了这件事 却打算视而不见
Because you received money from Branch Manager Tayama.
因为田山经理给你封口费
Or did you blackmail him?
不对 是因为你敲诈他了吧？
Blackmail?
敲诈？
Stop insulting me!
你可别侮辱我啊！
How dare you say such a thing to me?
你怎么可以对我说那么无礼的话？
These are pictures printed from the security cameras in this branch.
这是从分行的监视器印出来的影像
This morning, Branch Manager Tayama withdrew 500,000 yen from an ATM,
田山经理今早 从提款机领出了五十万日元
went to the parking garage,
然后去了停车场
and gave it to Chief Himuro.
把钱交给了冰室主任
This 500,000 yen was hush money to overlook the bypass loan.
这五十万是希望你能隐瞒 逆回融资一事的封口费
Was it true, Branch Manager Tayama?
没错吧 田山经理？
Yes.
是的
Don't you still have that money inside your jacket?
那笔钱应该还在你的西装口袋里吧？
Will you show us what's in your pocket?
能让我们看一下你口袋里的东西吗？
Are you kidding me?
开什么玩笑？
I am not obligated to do that.
我没义务让你们看！
It's all a lie.
这些都是谎言
What is this nonsense?
这是什么闹剧？
Don't get me involved in this.
别把我牵扯进去！
With all due respect…
请恕我直言
you told me yesterday that
你昨天还跟我说
credit examination is to find and correct unforgivable errors
所谓的信用检查 就是在注重信誉的银行之中
in a bank, where trust is a priority.
找出并纠正不可存在的错误
You are the leader of credit examination.
身为信用检查主任的你
But instead of finding an error and correcting it,
不仅没有纠正错误
you took money and overlooked it.
反而还收钱当作没一回事
You're doing the opposite.
你这样 就是说一套做一套！
-Shut up! -No, I won't!
-住嘴！ -我不要！
Before correcting the branch,
在纠正各分行的问题之前
you should correct your own errors.
你应该先纠正自身的过错
Making Tokyo Daiichi Bank better is your job?
你说你要让东京第一银行变得更好？
Give me a break.
真是天大的玩笑
This bank will never get better, because of people like you.
就是因为有你这样的人 这家银行才没办法变好
Excuse me.
失礼了
This is the money… right?
是钱呢
It looks like it's about 500,000 yen.
看起来正好有五十万左右
Hanasaki!
花琦
Etou?
江藤
Hanasaki. Mr. Soma. Thank you very much.
花琦、相马先生 谢谢你们
No. It's all thanks to you, Etou.
不 这都是你的功劳 江藤
We couldn't have done anything without that IOU.
没有那张本票的话 我们也做不了什么
Your passion moved President Natsume to action.
多亏你的诚意打动了夏目社长
No.
过奖了
You're not a half-baked banker.
你才不是什么半吊子
You are competent.
是很能干的融资职员
Thank you.
谢谢
Hanasaki.
花琦
Tell your father that I will go to his restaurant.
跟你爸爸说 我会再光顾你们的店
Senior Executive Director called us to come to his office…
堂岛专务叫我们去办公室找他
Is he going to scold us?
是要训我们话吗？
I don't know.
不知道啊
SENIOR EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR'S OFFICE
（专务董事办公室）
You are in the Branch Inspection, right?
你们两位就是分行稽核班的吧？
Yes. I am Soma.
是的 我是相马
I am Mai Hanasaki.
我是花琦舞
I see. You did a great job.
这样啊 辛苦你们了
Not at all.
不会
-Excuse me.
-打扰了
Executive Director Shindo, I was waiting for you.
真藤常务 我在等你呢
You called for me?
找我有事吗？
I was just thanking them for their recent work.
我正在夸奖他们这次的事做得很好
I see.
是吗？
I thought you'd also want to thank the Branch Inspection.
我猜 你也想谢谢分行稽核班吧？
I heard that you were taking good care of the Branch Manager at Fukagawa.
听说你很关照 深川分行的那位分行经理呢
I wasn't really taking care of him.
我也没有特别关照他啦
These two solved the scandal that happened in the Fukagawa Branch.
这次深川分行的丑闻 是他们两位解决的
Thanks to them, it didn't become public, and it spared our bank from disgrace.
多亏了他们 事情才没有闹大 避免损害银行的声誉
I think we should thank them. Don't you?
我们应该好好感谢他们 不是吗？
I see.
没错
I think you are right.
你说得对
I appreciate it.
真的得好好感激你们才是
Thank you.
谢谢
Not at all.
-过奖了
Excuse me.
我先告辞了
I am looking forward to your future endeavors. Work hard.
我很期待你们今后的表现 继续加油
Yes.
-是
He is declaring war against me.
他这是要宣战呢
Yes?
是
This is only the beginning.
现在才刚开始呢
Mr. Doujima said that?
堂岛专务竟然这样说？
You two did a great job.
你们干得不错呢
-Not much.
-没什么啦
Mr. Tayama was dispatched to Tokyo First Electrics.
田山经理被调遣到东京第一电厂
Mr. Himuro is now under HR investigation
而冰室主任正在接受人事部调查
to reveal all of his misconduct.
试图揭发他之前的所有不当行为
I see.
原来如此
By the way, it seems like Mr. Soma predicted correctly.
话说回来 相马你的预测挺准确的
About you.
他之前是这么说的
It's better not to tell Hanasaki.
最好别让花琦知道吧？
I agree. She's too transparent.
她行事太明显了
Yes.
是啊
And plus, if there's any wrongdoing at the branch
而且 就算我们不事先跟她说
Hanasaki will definitely find out,
要是分行有什么问题
whether we tell her beforehand or not.
她也一定会发现的
Did I say such a thing?
我说过这样的话吗？
I see, Mr. Soma is praising me when I'm not around.
原来相马还在我背后夸我呢
No, I didn't praise you.
不是 我这不是夸你
Don't get it wrong.
你别误会了
Don't be shy.
别害羞嘛
I didn't.
都说不是了
I just said that your unnecessary
我的意思是你那多余的所作所为
actions work out occasionally.
偶尔对事情有帮助啦
-Occasionally? It happens a lot. -What are you talking about?
-偶尔？明明是常常发生呢 -才不是
You have an inspection to go to.
你们两个还要去稽核呢
-Excuse me.
-我们先走了
Work hard!
拜托你们了！
Minowa Branch. Meaning lunch is eel.
三之轮分行啊 那午餐就吃鳗鱼了
Minowa… Eel is not bad. Curry is good there too.
三之轮啊 鳗鱼很好 咖喱也不错呢
Hey, look at this.
等等
There is a famous restaurant with horse meat hot pot.
你看这个 有名的樱花锅餐厅
That's it.
那就吃这个了
But it's hot today. Should we have eel?
不过 今天天气这么热 是不是吃鳗鱼比较好呢？
I want horse meat hot pot.
还是樱花锅好了
Okay. Let's be fair and allow the winner to choose.
好 为了公平起见 赢的那个决定吧
That's fine with me.
没问题
-Rock, paper, scissors!
-剪刀、石头、布
It was stolen?
被偷了吗？
An information leak from our bank?
我们银行泄露了资讯呢
It's your fault.
所有责任都在你身上
I got an X-mark.
这可是个大污点呢
The culprit is here.
犯人就在这家店里？
His passion for work became his downfall.
那家伙的工作热情让他倒大霉了
Why isn't his hard work paying off?
把认真努力工作的人当傻子
That's wrong!
这是大错特错！